<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous Items</name>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="ITEMS-JMBREW.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/herloveface/Aurora/master/JMBrew/ITEMS-JMBREW.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Changeling Cothes, Minor" type="Magic Item" source="JMBrew" id="ID_JMBREW_CCMIN_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>These clothes have the ability to change into any style, color and type of clothing in appearence.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action you can change the appearence of your clothing.</p>
			<p class="indent">The change is an illusion and as such does not grant you any bonuses to armor or any other benifits of a magical nature even if used to replicate the style of a magic attire.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>			
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Changeling Cothes, Major" type="Magic Item" source="JMBrew" id="ID_JMBREW_CCMAJ_WONDER">
		<description>
			<p>These clothes have the ability to change into any style, color and type of clothing in appearence.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action can change the appearence of your clothing.</p>
			<p class="indent">The change is a physical one and can grant you the AC bonus if the new form is that of Armor provided you have that armor proficiency.</p>
			<p class="indent">The clothing gains the weight of whatever form it is in.</p>		
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ring of the Luckless" type="Magic Item" source="JMBrew" id="ID_JMBREW_ROL_RINGS">
		<description>
			<p>This ring resembles a band of silver and gold with a yellow and red stone set into it. Casting identify reveals the following information (not the curse itself but if furhter research is done history shows that ever weilder of this ring has met an unseemly fate.) While attuned to this ring you can roll an additional 1d20 and add it to any skill check or attack roll made.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse. </em></strong>If the ring is used your DM rolls a 1d20 and subtracts their results from your overall total.</p>
			<p class="indent">If remove curse or dispel is cast on this ring the powers bound in it fade away over 1d10 minutes and the ring reverts to a non-magical form.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>